A Guide to the Records of the Drummond Brothers and Other Firms Located in Accomack County, Virginia, and Elsewhere, 1817-1879
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Records of the Drummond Brothers and Other Firms Located in Accomack County, Virginia, and Elsewhere 1817-1879
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-1
This collection consists of 24 volumes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University Library as a gift by the Division of State and Historical Research, United States Department of Agriculture in October, 1936.
Scope and Content
Ledgers, daybooks, cashbooks, and journals of general merchandise stores located at Grape-on-Hunting Creek, Centreville, and Wiseville, Va., relating to the grain, potato, and lumber trade. Includes the firms of Drummond Bros., James Dix, John Y. Bagwell, Segar & Goffigon, and accounts for business in Baltimore, Md., and Washington, D.C.
Contents List
- Account book, recording purchases and credits, presumably for sales of miscellaneous. 1837-1839
- Account book, dated Centreville each page. Records sales or charges, name of customer, items sold. 1837-1839
- Account book, dated Centreville each page. 1839-1841
- Cash book; and account book of sales; Wiseville each page; added entries; scattered throughout, and unlike rest of volume recording commodities. 1839-1847, 1855, dated 1867-1870
- Account book, dated Hunting Creek each page, records transactions by date, customer, commodity and price. 1842-1847
- Account book, dated Hunting Creek each page. 1841-1844
- Account book, dated Hunting Creek each page. 1844-1849
- Account book, dated Centre Hill each page, and 1852-1854, dated Hunting Creek each page. 1828-1830
- Account book, perhaps Accomack County, entries give date, customers, charges, merchandise. Perhaps kept by John & H. Bagwell and James H. P. Dix & Levi D. Dix. 1817-1825
- Account book, as preceding, kept by John Y. Bagwell. 1825-1828
- Account book, mostly record of purchases of dry goods etc., some in New York, N.Y also "An Inventory of Goods Sold Jno. E. Nottingham & John Simkins, August 2nd. 1833," hardware, books, cloth, playing cards. 1830-1833
- Account book, showing customer, date, amount, no commodity, Segar & Goffingon. 1830-1833
- Accounts, 1842-1849, cash books; 1857-1858 accounts, dated Wiseville each page, date, customer, commodity, price. Eariler part notes sales in Baltimore. 1842-1858
- Account book, notes date, customer, amount only. 1842-1851
- Account book, pages through Jan. 1859 dated Wiseville, rest are not; date, customer, commodity charges. 1855-1859
- Account book, numerous entries on dealings in Baltimore. 1836-1860
- Account book, mostly record of postal charges. Added entries in pencil 1861 dated Wiseville, date, customer, commodity, price. 1838-1853
- dated Centreville, 1851-1852 dated Hunting Creek. 1831-1835
- Tally-book(?), evidently of a dealer in grain. 1844-1852
- Account book, each page dated Hunting Creek: date, customer, commodity, prices. 1847-1853
- Account book, evidently of Drummond & Co. 1867-1872
- Account book, evidently of Ayres & Co., date, customer, charges, no items; account of cash. 1864-1867
- Account book, Drummond & Gunter, Wiseville (few added entries, 1881): date, customer, item, price. 1877-1879
- Account book. Date customer charges, no items. 1850-1864